Mss.973.3.H33n Mss.973.3.H33n
American Philosophical Society
A note on the history of the Jefferson manuscript draught of the Declaration of Independence in the Library of the American Philosophical Society, 1898
Mss.973.3.H33n
American Philosophical Society
1.0 Volume(s)
Accompanying this reprint from A.P.S. "Proceedings" 37(1898):88-107, are facsimilies of the Jefferson draft of the Declaration of Independence; 3 original letters from Richard Henry Lee, Jr., to John Vaughan, 1836 and 1840; an original letter from Isaac Lea to Vaughan, 1840; a note on the manuscript by Vaughan; and two original letters between Vaughan and George Combe, 1841.
1 volume.
Hays, I. Minis, (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
Volume 1
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Received and accessioned, 12/--/1900 (1900 2644).
Biographical/Historical note
I. Minis Hays was a Philadelphia physician and author and editor of books on medicine and Benjamin Franklin. He was Librarian of the American Philosophical Society from 1897 to 1922.
American Philosophical Society. Library.; Combe, George, 1788-1858; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886; Lee, Richard Henry, 1794-1865; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Personal histories.
- A note on the history of the Jefferson manuscript draught of the Declaration of independence in the library of the American philosophical society., 1898; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
  Scope and Contents note
  20p. facsim. F. Reprinted July 21, 1898 from the Proceedings - American philosophical society, v.37. f.p.
  - Letter to [J.W. ] Wallace, Oct. 26, 1825; 8 1/2" x 12 1/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Typed c. of L. 2p. (Bound with Hays, Note on the history... of the Declaration) Received letter from John Vaughan of the A.P.S. informing that R.H. Lee had deposited his grandfather's correspondence and papers, including Jefferson's draught of the Declaration of independence with the Society. (from original in Library of Congress.)
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 11, 1836; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Lee, Richard Henry, 1794-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. (Bound with Hays, Note on the history of...Declaration) Never had the original of the letter from Mr. Jefferson accompanying his draught of the Declaration. The copy sent the APS is an authentic one coming down from his grandfather. Proposal to reclaim Lee papers presented to the University of Virginia and give them to the APS. Proposed gift of Col. Morgan papers to the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 25, 1840; 8" x 10"; Lee, Richard Henry, 1794-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 4p., add., end. (Bound with Hays, Note on the history... of Declaration) Relative to the draught of the Declaration and the copy of Mr. Jefferson's letter presented to the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 24, 1840; 7 1/2" x 10"; Lee, Richard Henry, 1794-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. (Bound with Hays, Note on the history... of Declaration) Transcribes a statement relative to the draught of the Declaration in the Athenaeum [i.e. A.P.S.] Statement printed: Hays, Note on... Declaration...p.7.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 1, 1840; 10x8; Leet, Isaac
    Washington, A.L.S. 1P.and add.,end. (see Hays. Notes on the declaration... no.8.) Forwards statement concerning R.H. Lee's draft of the declaration in the hand of Jefferson.
  - Letter to Richard Henry Lee, Jan. 31, 1840; 7 1/2" x 12 1/2"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Phila., Copy of L. 3p. (Bound with Hays, Note on the history... of the Declaration) Relative to the draught of the Declaration of independence which Mr. Lee had presented to the Society,
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 23, 1841; 7 1/2" x 9"; Combe, George, 1788-1858
    Hull, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (Bound with Hays, Note on the history... of the Declaration) Acknowledges letter giving history of the American Declaration of Independence.
  - Letter to George Combe, March 27, 1841; 8" x 10"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Phila., A.Dr. of L. 2p. (Bound with Hays, Note on the history...of the Declaration) Relative to the draught of the Declaration of independence in Jefferson's hand in the possession of the APS.
  - Miscellaneous notes relative to the Declaration of independence and Jefferson's draughts, 1841; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    ca. A.D. 9p. var. sizes (Bound with Hays, Note on the history of the Declaration,no.10,11,12,15,16) Some of these notes may be by R.H. Lee.
  - Notes on the copy of the declaration in the hand of Jefferson, 1841; 13x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    [ca.?] A.D.S. 4p. (see Hays. Notes on the declaration...no.9.)